I have been here for 12 days to get the MBBS seat in this college.
I have come here to tell you what to do in these 12 days.
I have already conveyed the same thing to the repeater students of Eduport.
What I am trying to say here is that,
I will not take more than 15 minutes.
After seeing your respect for this,
the first thing I want to tell you is,
I have heard one thing from you.
While I was preparing for this,
I just searched on YouTube,
what do these students do?
What should we include?
I have about 10 or 20 videos.
In the last 10 days,
I have been trying to get 600 marks, 400 marks, 300 marks.
So, sometimes you can do that yourself.
You should do that first.
Stop all that.
Do it directly.
Do any one thing.
If you are convinced,
you can do only that.
There is a big difference.
Another person is saying,
you can do that.
If one person is convinced,
you will get a better point than the other.
We don't have time for that.
All you have to do is to study.
The case I am going to cover today is,
there are almost 4 categories of students
who have become NEET aspirants.
It is purely based on their performance.
I am not saying anything about this.
He is a repeater.
He is a first-hander.
I am not saying anything about this with Plastu.
That is,
based on your mark,
even if this mark comes true,
it is very relative.
It is not that easy to get a mark
in a very easy exam like 600+.
But,
what I mean by 600+,
is that,
even some of your students
will have come for sure.
For sure,
in your coaching centre,
in your tuition centre,
or wherever your results come from,
you will be at the top.
Even inside your heart,
you will have a desire
or you will have a confidence.
This year,
I will get a seat in any government medical college.
That is the first category.
What will they do?
The second case is
the bottom line.
If you try one more time,
you will reach the government medical college.
If you don't try,
you will have to repeat it for one more year.
That is,
those who are on the edge.
Because,
for them,
this is the most crucial.
What is the most crucial?
The effort of one year,
two years,
three years,
may be in the name of
two or three questions.
But,
that is not possible.
So,
the second case is
what those people have to do.
The third case is,
in their case,
they are getting
about 400 marks consistently.
It is 400 minus.
They are getting
between 400 and 300 MBs consistently.
But,
if you look at it this way,
if you are lucky enough
to get a seat in the government MBBS
after 12 days of struggle,
you will not get a seat in the government MBBS.
That is the reality.
If I say,
I am lucky enough to get a seat in the government MBBS,
I am lucky enough to get a seat in the government MBBS.
But,
some things have to be accepted.
For example,
if I study for 12 days
and want to get a seat in the government MBBS,
you will not get a seat in the government MBBS.
That is not the model.
I am just looking at it.
So,
you can see it.
what do they have to do?
And,
the fourth case,
other than this,
especially in repeaters,
there will be very few students.
Those who crash with
this year's plus two,
may be they will get
a mark in the range of
150 to 300.
So,
before I say
what they have to do,
this why is very important.
That is,
Sir,
I have got the MBBS.
Then,
what should I pay attention to?
What should I pay attention to?
If you are sure
to think about this,
that why is very important.
What the students need to understand
is that
you are sure that
my rank will be
in the range of 1500.
State rank will come.
If I get any medical college,
you can decide
which medical college
those 12 days
are.
These 12 days
of school
are
which medical college
you can decide.
Now,
what is the medical college
they will get?
Let me give you an example. My cousin and Rani, who is also associated with Eduport, are in a house emergency.
Rani's home is just 10 minutes away from Calicut Medical College.
Rani has studied at Calicut Medical College.
Think about it. If Rani gets Thiruvananthapura, no matter how good the college is or how many friends she has,
that convenience is a huge difference.
It is very important for you to get Thiruvananthapura Medical College rather than getting Calicut or Kannur.
Similarly, if you are in Calicut Medical College,
if you are in the state rank of 10 or 100,
if you are in the state rank of 10 and have not been admitted to AIMS for many years,
but if you are still trying to get admitted to AIMS,
you might be able to get admitted to the 90th or 100th rank of AIMS.
That is what you are going to get.
That is not very small. It is not that small.
It will have a huge impact.
I always say that the most positive thing that I have learned in NIT is that I was able to study in Calicut.
If you are in Thiruvananthapura or Alapuzha or Kottayam, you will not get this much of comfort.
Because I am from Calicut.
That is what I have to say in front of you.
I don't have to say anything in the case of Anjur.
That is to say,
if we start our work in May for a year,
or if we start our work in May for a year,
around this November,
when there are only 12 days left for the exams to start,
these 12 days will be an action to you.
Maybe you will succeed in achieving those efforts in those years.
Maybe you can get a Government Medical College.
In the case of NANUR,
you might get some great results.
The first thing is,
maybe you won't get the Government Medical College,
but by getting this 12 days, you could get admitted to a private Medical College.
If the family has the money,
If they are okay with it, then it is a good option.
The second option is, if you are a repeat student,
you will be able to study 100% free.
You might be thinking that you are only going to study for one year.
There are 2-3 batches in Eduport that are doing re-repeat.
In those 3 batches, there are people who do it for free.
There are people who close the hostel fees and repeat.
The confidence level and tension level of those who do it for free
are very different from those who do it for free.
Those who do it for free don't have a lot of tension.
They don't have the feeling that their parents don't give them money.
That is a very impactful thing.
You will be able to reach that level for sure.
You will learn well.
The next group is these people.
The range is between 180 and 300.
I am asking you for your purpose.
You are not intending to repeat next year.
In my knowledge, you have not done anything in the last 12 days.
Why are you doing it?
If anyone has any thoughts, you can comment here.
That is,
12 days.
If you have any thoughts, you can comment here.
If you are going to repeat in the same place,
this last category is definitely for you.
You can decide whether to repeat or not.
You will get confidence.
What each of them have to do is what I am going to say.
This is called strategy.
I think the first strategy I have to tell is this.
600 plus.
Or what is in my mind.
What is in my mind.
I think of people who are aware that they will get a Government Medical College.
The only thing you have to do is this.
That is writing M.O.C tests only.
Two years ago, I wrote M.O.C tests.
Two years ago, I got an All India Rank 1.
She is studying in Ames, Delhi.
In one of her interviews, she said that she had only done mock tests for the last 15 days.
She had done 3 daily mock tests.
Let me tell you one more thing.
I am not going to repeat this again.
If you think that she has only done mock tests for the last 15 days,
the rest of the people should also study for the next 15 days.
These 600 plus people should also study for the next 15 days.
If that is the case, you can do 3 daily mock tests.
3 mock tests consist of 9 hours.
Along with those 9 hours,
you can print out the mock test.
It will take another hour to complete the mock test.
The remaining 5 hours are for the evaluation of the mock test.
This is the main thing you should do.
Some students do not need to read the biology textbook.
They can write the mock test.
You can think about it.
When you see the questions in each mock test,
you will see the page in the biology textbook.
It may be the upper or the lower part.
You can say that the following statements are true.
It may be that there are 3 or 4 mistakes.
You should only do the active recall.
Now I will tell you two more things.
In the first case,
one of the mock tests should start at 2 p.m.
That is, the way you start your neat time.
You should do the mock test in the first case.
Now the second case.
What does the second case say?
The second case says that
you should do the mock test for 1 or 2 times.
Maximum 5 times.
You cannot do more than that.
You should do 10 times.
If there is a case where you have no confidence in 10 times,
you should give special attention to those 10 times.
What I usually do is,
I ask for the previous year questions which are specified in the mock test.
Previous year questions may have been seen by you
when you reach 600+.
If you're not able to do those questions,
you can take the chapter-wise questions from the study materials.
If you fail to do that,
you can look at the textbook.
You can change the time to study this properly.
If so, you can reduce these three mock tests to two.
You can try to study the rest of the lessons.
This is it.
When you touch a chapter-specific question in Code Motion in a straight line,
you may have to go to Thiruvantharam Medical College.
You may have to go to Kannur or Malappuram or Manjeri.
You may have to go to Kozhikode Medical College.
You can do it without doing that.
If this is clear to you,
let's move on to the second group.
500.
500 plus.
In the case of 500 plus,
there is a lack of confidence in some lessons.
There is a lack of confidence in some lessons.
What is there in some lessons?
It is to know well.
What do you have to do?
What do you have to do with one mock test every day from 2 pm to 5 pm?
You have to keep me out of the mock test.
Okay.
When we talk about the case of mock test,
there is one thing.
It is not just writing a mock test.
If you write a mock test,
where did you go wrong?
Especially for students of 600 marks.
Sometimes the concept is wrong.
Sometimes there is a minus.
Sometimes one byte is forgotten.
Each question.
You don't have to think about the correct question.
The wrong questions.
The questions that you don't know.
Why is it wrong?
Why?
What is it that I don't understand there?
Looking at that,
it is to learn one more thing.
That is the most important thing in mock test.
Once again,
to say it well.
That is,
the importance of the mock test.
To write the mock test.
To see more questions.
How many people are there?
The wrong questions.
The questions that we don't know.
The questions that we correct.
Why is it wrong?
I still remember.
That is,
a question to see kinetic energy.
Because,
in the entrance exam,
in the mock test,
not in the mock test,
but in the class,
they teach kinetic energy.
The equation of half mv squared.
So,
in the hurry of seeing m and v,
I quickly gave the answer
in mv squared.
But,
I got it wrong.
Because,
I had forgotten to put half.
But,
since then,
when the question of kinetic energy
arises,
my mind was with me.
Why?
Because,
I had forgotten half.
So,
what is this thing?
Even now,
for you,
Okay.
Even now,
what you have to do is,
you have to do this thing.
Hey,
if someone asks,
I don't do mock test.
Whichever category you belong to,
this will come.
This is the thing.
What do you have to do next?
You have to do it.
In the case of mock test.
So,
if you are above 500,
you will surely get it.
You may not get a lot.
The answer is wrong.
Maybe,
you may not know.
So,
you have to learn that topic completely.
That is,
in mock test,
the students in this category,
if they don't get it in mock test,
what if it goes wrong?
From that topic,
if I still get the question,
for example,
you have average velocity.
When you see average velocity,
you forget the equation.
Otherwise,
you don't get it.
So,
that chapter,
that topic,
if you look at it again,
even if you get another question,
it will go wrong.
Equations of motion.
Average velocity symbols.
A question is wrong.
You have to understand that.
What is the use of equations of motion?
Motion under gravity.
If you get another question there,
don't think that you will get it wrong.
Then,
you can do 5-6,
10 questions on that topic.
This is what you have to do
in mock test.
Then,
the second case is,
what is it?
You have to do chapters
with less knowledge
and confidence.
You have to do practice questions.
But,
when you do practice questions here,
the most important weapon
is to say,
skip.
That is,
students,
you have to understand that
if I have to come in front of you
and talk like this,
one of the most important factors
in that is
that I have entered
NIT.
That is the turning point
in my life.
The most important factor
to enter NIT
is the skip.
That is,
at the end,
you have to think
that I have to write this
with a plus 2.
So,
after plus 2,
one month,
when we study,
in the case of
studying a topic
that we did not know
previously,
it will not end
in any way.
But,
I will take
a question
in the straight line
of motion.
When we take
the straight line of motion,
okay,
the average velocity,
no matter which book you take,
there is no other question
about the average velocity.
2 V1 V2
by V1 plus V2.
There will be
5 or 10 questions
about that.
And,
in the first case,
if a boy goes to school
and comes back home,
in the next case,
a man goes to the shop
and comes back home.
In the other case,
another person comes
after half the distance.
So,
in these 5 cases,
same equations,
same formula,
same answer
will come.
Otherwise,
it is that thing.
So,
after reading the question,
if this is 2 V1 V2
by V1 plus V2,
what should we do?
We should not attend to it.
We should skip it.
What will happen if we skip it?
You will get a lot of questions
in the confusion
that you do not know.
In other words,
another question
may come like this.
What is one person
who goes to
half the distance
in V1
and the other half
in V2
and the next
in V3?
Do you think
you can do this?
You can do
only these questions.
You can finish
and practice.
Then,
most importantly,
there is no need
for tension.
At this stage,
in the next
May 3,
those who clear
your exams
and reach
the top rank
will be
Harshar.
Harshar,
you are in this case.
You are coming
in this.
I will tell you
what to do.
Okay.
But,
the flow will go.
The flow will go.
You are in this stage.
You do it
in the next 12 days
in this plan.
So,
you may feel
the mock test
will fail
if the knowledge
from the chapter
is wrong.
All that is normal.
But,
to prevent
this from happening
in the May 3,
you should do this.
Practice the unknown chapters
in the mock test.
What has to happen is
if you have
completed
3 or 4 chapters
in today's
mock test,
what should you
do in the next
Make sure that it is not wrong.
As I said earlier, evaluate.
This is the only thing you need to do.
And at some point,
if you finish these chapters,
you can increase the number of mock tests.
When you study for 15 hours,
if you have two more chapters to study after writing two mock tests,
it is okay to do so.
Ultimately, check the chapters with less confidence.
There is nothing in the equation book.
I am saying this seriously.
Many people,
when the equation book is up to this point,
remember to read the book carefully.
The equation book is made up of
equations and questions.
In my case,
I have done so many questions
that I cannot remember which one is 2V1, V2, V1 plus V2.
At that time,
I did not remember this thing.
You will find this in all the equation books.
It is used in many cases.
So, remember to do it.
By heart,
you should not study new equations by heart.
You should not talk about the philosophy of science.
Next is the third case.
The third category is
400+.
Children,
if you have a mark of 400+,
what is your problem?
You do not know many chapters.
Similarly,
all the chapters do not have marks.
Let me ask you again.
What is your biology mark?
It is 360, isn't it?
This biology,
that is,
you have bought this 400+,
after studying for 12 days and 15 hours,
you want to match up something,
these are the two cases.
Either in a private seat
or in a BDSO,
you will get things.
Or you can do it free of cost.
Even for these two,
you have to score marks in biology.
If your biology mark is 360,
you have to focus more on biology.
Biology, biology, biology,
keep studying.
what is that?
Keep studying.
In those 300,
you can get 300 marks.
No,
you can get a 300 mark out of 360.
Even with the rest,
you can get 150 to 200 marks.
If that is the first case,
then what can you do?
In chemistry,
what are the chapters
that you liked the most?
What are the chapters
that you were told
from your weight age?
Weight age is not like that.
What can you do in that?
Focus on 6 to 10 chapters.
How can you focus on chapters?
It is the same thing.
Okay.
Then,
what do you have to study in physics?
You have to study only
modern physics.
If you study this,
if you study this,
in the next 12 days,
what will it be?
You can reach the range
of 450 to 500.
Okay.
Sometimes,
you will get in.
You will not get in.
If you get in,
you will not know
how much you know.
But,
focus on biology.
Try to get 300 marks in biology.
In chemistry,
6 to 10 chapters
in physics,
in modern physics.
Then,
what do you have to do
in mock tests?
In mock tests,
the test is repeated.
So,
there are chances to get it.
Unfortunately,
we have reached that stage.
So,
you have to do it
in the last,
in April.
After 30,
you have to do
3 to 4 mock tests.
Only to know
what happens
when a test is done.
Then,
you do not have to do anything else.
You do not have to do anything else.
Now,
now,
Sir,
this year's exam will be tough.
I have nothing to say.
It is
in my opinion,
it will not be that tough
in the previous year.
It will not be that easy
It will be in the middle.
But,
it can be tough
even now.
It can be tough
It can be very easy even now.
And,
this year is
unpredictable.
Okay.
Now,
next.
Next is
the last type.
What is the last type
of test?
The last type of test
is
students
in the 200 range.
Students in the 200 range
have to do
this.
This is
what you have to do.
You have to
study biology
as much as you can.
But,
do not just study biology.
Because,
what is our intention?
To repeat or not?
You have to decide that.
If you have already
repeated this score,
you should not try it again.
This is my
personal opinion.
This is not a reality.
If you are
students in the 200 range,
what will you do in biology?
You have to do
about
30 things.
You have to do
about 10 things.
Similarly,
in chemistry,
you have to do
about
4 things.
Similarly,
in physics,
you have to do
about
2 lessons in
the first year
and then
you have to
study modern physics.
This is all you have to do.
You can do
mock tests
if you want.
But,
when you
try this chapter,
you may not get it.
I know that.
When you
try this chapter,
you have
some confidence.
Earlier,
I said that
we had Chaitan.
Chaitan is
our first
repeater bachelor
in top rank.
Now,
I have decided to
repeat Chaitan
in top rank.
After the
second year,
I asked my friends
what to do.
They said
that we can
just go
for crash.
He has a 90%
mark above me.
So,
I went for crash
when I got a scholarship.
For the
NEET after crash,
he has 223 marks.
I said
in the fourth category.
But,
even with 223 marks,
one thing
was sure for me.
If I repeat it
for a year,
I will be able
to do it.
That is what
you need.
Now,
if you
want to
increase
your mark,
you can
study only biology.
But,
even if you
study only biology,
your chemistry
and physics
will be very bad.
So,
next year,
there might be
a repeater.
So,
you have to
combine these
three and
do it.
And,
lastly,
I have not
mentioned
any point
in the video.
But,
still,
what we are doing
is,
we are giving
our classes
for the next
10 days.
If anyone
is able to do it,
what is the point
that I always say?
If you have studied
fully,
you will know
how to
see the results
and how to
approach questions.
Organic Chemist
and Chefin sir
are going to take maximum.
They will do
a good job.
Now,
some students
will start
at 9.
Don't tell
them that
they have
finished a mock test
and have
done some
studies.
They will start
at 12.
I can't see
2X even
when I enter
live.
I will go to
2X and
skip and
see.
You will know
all the questions.
Similarly,
if I am not
seeing this
live,
the questions
discussed in
this
are hand
picked
questions.
That is the only thing
you have to
look at.
You don't have
to watch
the live
for the
first time
with a
single
YouTube channel
or 8.
Because
you won't
learn
how useful
these
live
are.
Similarly,
it is very
important
for you
to see
the questions
in this
live.
You can
skip
the live
and
see the
questions
that are
asked
in this
live.
In my opinion,
these questions
are the
most important.
See,
they are doing
it with
that much effort.
If the
top 500
in organic
chemistry
is the
top 300
questions
in
organic
chemistry,
then
the
top 300
in
organic
chemistry
are
the
most
important
questions
in
organic
chemistry.
The
second
case is
in
organic
chemistry.
What
is
the
most
expected
question
in
physics?
This
is
a
shortcut
for
botany.
Botany has
500 questions
in
zoology.
This
is
one
bite
and
the
next
one.
This
is
a
mistake.
This
is
a
one
bite.
This
is
what
you
have
to
do.
This is
a
very
simple
question.
This
question
will help
you a
lot.
Ultimately,
if
you claim
your
rank,
you are
the
winner.
Okay,
bye.